<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>System Administration</title>
  <para>Before you can begin processing Time and Expense Sheets, you must
  first set up the system with Expense Items, create Employees, and configure
  appropriate User Permissions. These activities should be completed by a
  manager responsible for time and expense―or dedicated information technology
  professional. In this chapter, we'll cover the following topics:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Setting up Expense Items</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Configuring Employees</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Configuring User Permissions</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Once these configurations are complete, you can begin entering Time
  and Expense Sheets!</para>
  <section>
    <title>Expense Item Setup</title>
    <para>In order to use items for Project expenses, you need to create or
    edit existing reference Items and map expense accounts to the General
    Ledger. To demonstrate how this is done, we will use examples taken from
    the xTuple demo database. To begin, follow the steps below:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Follow this path: <guimenuitem>Products &gt; Item &gt;
        List...</guimenuitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select an existing Reference item, or create a new Reference
        item. For this example, we'll select the MILEAGE item.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The Project tab is only available for reference Item
          Types.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "Project" tab.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para><screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/expenseItem.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Expense Item Setup</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot></para>
    <para>Once the "Allow use as Expense Item on Projects" has been selected,
    the Project tab provides the ability to select a specific Account or
    Expense Category.</para>
    <note>
      <para>In order to track costs for a Project, an account or category MUST
      be selected for the Item.</para>
    </note>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>ACCOUNT</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Identify a General Ledger (G/L) Account to be used for
          expensing Purchasing Expenses to. This is an Expense Account. This
          Account will be used to create distributions when Vouchering expense
          lines. The account will be debited when the Voucher is
          posted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>EXPENSE CATEGORY</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Identify an Expense Category to distribute Purchasing Expenses
          to. The Expense Category is used to define a set of General Ledger
          (G/L) Accounts related to an expense. This Account will be used to
          create distributions when Vouchering expense lines. The account will
          be debited when the Voucher is posted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Configuring Employees</title>
    <para>Configuring Employees in xTuple is a critical component of the Time
    and Expense package, since Time Sheets are associated with Employees. Only
    users who are set up as an Employee and have the correct level of
    permissions will have the ability to track their time. Again, our example
    will focus on users found in the xTuple demo database.</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>To get started go to <guilabel>System &gt; Employees &gt;
        List...</guilabel></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/employees.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>List Employees</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>To create a new Employee, simply select the NEW button and enter the
    required Employee information. The following screen will appear:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/employee.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Employee</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The first information you will be asked to enter is the Contact
    information for the Employee. If that information already exists, you can
    look it up and add it from this screen. Or if it does not already exist,
    then you can manually enter the information now.</para>
    <para>In order to create Vouchers to compensate Employees for expenses
    performed according to their Time Sheets, the Employee must be selected as
    a Vendor. Click on the "Detail" tab and select the "Vendor" option, as
    shown in the next screenshot:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/employeevendor.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Employee Vendor</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Once you have indicated you want to link the Employee to a Vendor
    record, select the VENDOR button. This will launch the Vendor screen,
    where you can enter detailed Vendor information.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/employeevendor2.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Vendor Information</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Getting back to the Employee screen, select the "Financial" tab to
    enter financial information. Keep in mind that in order to track the cost
    of Employee time as an expense, the Employee must NOT be flagged as a
    Contractor and the compensation field must have a value of zero.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/contractor.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Employee Financial</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Once you have finished entering Employee information, you are ready
    to assign permissions.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="configurePermissions">
    <title>Configuring User Permissions</title>
    <para>xTuple ERP has the powerful ability to manage user permissions,
    enabling you to allow or disallow access to various functional areas of
    the system. For example, a clerk may enter time and expense, while a
    manager may have the ability to approve entries.</para>
    <para>There are several options available to you when managing system
    users. You can either A) assign individual permissions to users B) create
    preconfigured groups of permissions and assign individuals to these groups
    or C) a combination of A and B.</para>
    <para>The following path will get you to the screen for maintaining system
    users: <guimenuitem>System &gt; Maintain Users</guimenuitem>.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/tepermissions.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>List Users</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>In this scenario, let's say we have a new Employee whose permissions
    we want to review. To begin, follow these steps:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight the user whose permissions we want to review</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the EDIT button (or double-click on the user)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/tepermissions2.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>User Privileges</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>As you can see, the basic user information—such as name and email
    address—has already been entered. The user has the ability to enter their
    own time and expenses, which you can see under the "Granted Privileges"
    section. We can add or remove privileges (by module) simply by selecting a
    specific privilege, and then choosing either the ADD or REVOKE
    button.</para>
    <tip>
      <para>Use the ADD ALL and REVOKE ALL buttons to move all the privileges
      at once for the specified module</para>
    </tip>
    <para>The user role feature makes it easy to define logical sets of
    privileges defined according to standard job roles. The following path
    takes you to the screen for defining role privileges: <guimenuitem>System
    &gt; Maintain Roles</guimenuitem>. More information regarding Role setup,
    please consult the <ulink
    url="http://www.xtuple.org/docs/reference-guide">xTuple ERP Reference
    Guide</ulink>.</para>
    <tip>
      <para>Time and Expense entry is closely integrated with Projects and
      Tasks. Users that are granted privileges to Time and Expense entry
      should also be granted MaintainProjects and ViewProjects in the CRM
      module.</para>
    </tip>
  </section>
</chapter>
