<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>Employee Costs</title>
  <para>In order to track the cost of an Employee's time as a Project expense,
  your system must be configured to appropriately map these expenses to your
  Chart of Accounts. In this chapter we will review how to configure CRM
  module to capture these costs, process Time Sheets, and review the General
  Ledger.</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Configure CRM Module</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Process Time Sheets</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Review General Ledger</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <section>
    <title>How to Configure the CRM Module</title>
    <para>In order to track labor overhead costs you must be sure to configure
    the CRM module to accommodate this. Follow the steps below:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Open module by selecting <guilabel>CRM &gt;
        Setup...</guilabel></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/crmmodule.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Employee CRM Setup</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Select an appropriate expense account for Project Labor And
    Overhead.</para>
    <note>
      <para>If an expense account is not selected you will be unable to post
      Employee overhead costs to the General Ledger.</para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Process Time Sheets</title>
    <para>Once items are mapped to a Project expense account and Employees are
    set up with a compensation value (See System Administration chapter) then
    you are ready to post time to the General Ledger. Follow these steps to
    process an approved Time Sheet.</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Follow this path: <guimenuitem>CRM &gt; Project &gt; Time and
        Expense...</guimenuitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select approved status</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click QUERY</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/approvetimepost.PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Open Sheets</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>Highlight the Sheet to be processed check the Post Time box at the
    bottom of the screen and select the PROCESS button or right-click and
    select "Post Time."</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Review General Ledger</title>
    <para>Once Time Sheets have been processed, you can verify whether
    Employee costs have been posted as an expense by reviewing the General
    Ledger transaction reports.</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>To locate the General Ledger report, follow this path:
        <guimenuitem>Accounting &gt; General Ledger &gt; Reports &gt;
        Transactions...</guimenuitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click QUERY</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/gltransactions.PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>General Ledger Transactions</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>You will notice the Time Sheet number and transactions are now
    posted to the General Ledger as an expense.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Conclusion</title>
    <para>The xTuple Time and Expense module is a powerful free component of
    the xTuple ERP, CRM, and accounting software that allows businesses to
    track, invoice, and pay professional services time-and-related expenses,
    tightly integrated with the Project Management subsystem of xTuple CRM. If
    you have questions about xTuple software, or would like to discuss
    training, support, or potential enhancements to the software, please
    contact <ulink
    url="mailto:sales@xtuple.com">sales@xtuple.com</ulink>.</para>
    <para>Thank you for your interest in xTuple ERP.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
