<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>Installation</title>

  <section>
    <title>Overview</title>

    <para>Time and Expense—otherwise known as <literal>xtte</literal>—is an
    xTuple extension package which may be applied to any xTuple ERP edition:
    PostBooks, Standard, or Manufacturing. The package is easy to install. And
    once installed, it seamlessly integrates time and expense functionality
    with your ERP.</para>

    <note>
      <para>For this chapter we will assume you have already installed xTuple
      ERP, version 3.6.0 or higher.</para>
    </note>

    <para>To install Time and Expense, you will need the following
    items:</para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Updater tool</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>This is the package installer. It is a cross-platform
          application which connects to your xTuple ERP database and installs
          the Time and Expense package (<literal>xtte</literal>). The Updater
          is the same tool that is used for upgrading xTuple ERP databases
          from one version to the next. It also converts xTuple ERP from one
          edition to the next (e.g., PostBooks to Standard).</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Time and Expense package (xtte)</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>This is the extension package which integrates time and
          expense features with your xTuple ERP. The file is loaded into the
          Updater, which in turn applies the package to your xTuple database.
          And like all xTuple database upgrade scripts, the file ends with a
          <filename><literal>.gz</literal></filename> extension.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Getting the Required Files</title>

    <para>The Updater tool can be downloaded from the PostBooks project page
    on SourceForge.net. To reach the PostBooks project, follow these
    steps:</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Point your web browser to <ulink
        url="http://sourceforge.net/">http://sourceforge.net/</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Search for the PostBooks project</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Or use the direct URL: <ulink
        url="???">http://sourceforge.net/projects/postbooks/</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The following project page will appear:</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/sourceforge.png" />
      </imageobject>

      <caption>PostBooks Project Home Page</caption>
    </mediaobject>

    <para>Next, click on the "View all files" button (the smaller one,
    adjacent to the big green button). This will give you access to all the
    available folders. In the following screenshot, the Updater is folder
    #06:</para>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/sourceforge2.png" />
      </imageobject>

      <caption>PostBooks Folders Download Page</caption>
    </mediaobject>

    <para>Finally, expand the link for the latest version of the Updater
    folder (they should be in reverse chronological order, most recent first).
    Be sure to choose a download which corresponds to your operating system.
    The following screen shows version 2.2.2 of the Updater, available for
    Mac, Windows, or Linux:</para>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/sourceforge3.png" />
      </imageobject>

      <caption>Download Updater</caption>
    </mediaobject>

    <para>Once you've downloaded the Updater and the <literal>xtte</literal>
    package, you are ready to begin the installation!</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Installing the Package</title>

    <para>Having xTuple ERP installed and running is a prerequisite for
    installing Time and Expense. Assuming this is the case, then you are ready
    to begin.</para>

    <note>
      <para>Before you install the Time and Expense package, you should first
      make a backup copy of your xTuple ERP database. This way you can always
      restore the backup copy should you encounter problems during the
      installation process.</para>
    </note>

    <para>To begin installing the Time and Expense package, the first step is
    to connect the Updater to your xTuple ERP database. The process for
    connecting is identical to the process used when logging in using your
    xTuple ERP client software.</para>

    <para>The following screen shows the log in screen you are presented with
    when launch the Updater application:</para>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/updaterLogin.png" />
      </imageobject>

      <caption>Connect to xTuple Database Using Updater</caption>
    </mediaobject>

    <tip>
      <para>If you are having trouble connecting to your xTuple ERP database
      with the Updater, select the OPTIONS button on the Log In screen to
      ensure your connection information is correct.</para>
    </tip>

    <para>Once you successfully connect to the database, you are ready to load
    the <literal>xtte</literal> package. To begin loading the
    <literal>xtte</literal> package, follow these steps:</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "File" menu option</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select the "Open" option</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <para>Once you locate the <literal>xtte</literal> package on your file
    system (e.g., <filename><filename>xtte-2.0.0.gz</filename></filename>), a
    short series of prerequisite checks will be performed. The following
    screen shows the results of a successful prerequisite check:</para>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/updatemanage.png" />
      </imageobject>

      <caption>Update Manager and Package</caption>
    </mediaobject>

    <para>If the prerequisite check was successful, simply select the START
    UPDATE button to complete installation. Depending on the quality of your
    network connection, this final step of the installation process should
    complete quickly.</para>

    <note>
      <para>Contact your system administrator if you encounter errors or
      extreme slowness after selecting the START UPDATE button.</para>
    </note>

    <para>To verify the Time and Expense package has been successfully
    installed, log into xTuple ERP. Finally, navigate to the installed
    packages directory, using the following path: <guimenuitem>System &gt;
    Design &gt; Packages</guimenuitem>. If Time and Expense was installed
    correctly, the package should appear as shown in the following
    screen:</para>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/listpackages.png" />
      </imageobject>

      <caption>Package Installed in xTuple ERP</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </section>
</chapter>
