<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<preface>
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <section>
    <title>Product Overview</title>
    <para>Project Management requires the ability to account for the hours and
    expenses related to a Project. While these capabilities are critical to
    Project Management, they're even more important to a business operating in
    the Service industry. Manufacturing companies have had many tools
    available for product costing and profitability reporting for decades. The
    Time and Expense extension delivers a comparable level of reporting
    required by services businesses.</para>
    <para>Time and Expense provides service-based functionality on top of the
    foundation of xTuple ERP. In addition to the features found in Time and
    Expense, you also have access to the full range of advanced ERP
    features&mdash;such as accounting, inventory management, and Customer
    relationship management (CRM).</para>
    <para>Here are just a few real world examples of how Time and Expense can
    help you:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Budget management by Project and Task</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Time and Expense will enable you to report budget vs actual
          information for a Project and Task. Requiring hours and expenses to
          be assigned to a Project and Task can greatly enhance your ability
          to manage costs and Project margins.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Improved Cash Flow</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Capturing service billing in a routine manner allows for
          faster invoicing. The ability to enter detailed notes on each time
          or expense line provides supporting documentation, which fosters
          better communication and faster cash receipts.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Enhanced Expense Management</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Employees can enter expenses and associate them to a Project.
          A manager can then use the Approval process once they've reviewed
          the entries. Expenses can then be automatically vouchered and a
          payment processed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para>This Time and Expense Product Guide will walk you through the
    process of installing, configuring, and using Time and Expense for your
    service billing and expense reporting needs.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Choosing an xTuple ERP Edition</title>
    <para>Time and Expense is available for use by all three xTuple ERP
    editions: PostBooks, Standard, and Manufacturing. This means you will have
    full-scale ERP functionality underlying your Time and Expense
    installation.</para>
    <para>If you are uncertain which xTuple ERP edition is the right one for
    you, our sales staff would be happy to help you make your decision. To
    contact us, simply send an email requesting more information to <ulink
    url="mailto:sales@xtuple.com">sales@xtuple.com</ulink>.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Open Source Software: What is it and what does it mean to
    me?</title>
    <para>By now you may have heard some buzz about open source
    software&mdash;and you're not sure what to make of it. It may even sound
    like a bunch of technical jargon used to impress IT professionals, which
    may or may not apply to yourself. This is all the more reason why we want
    to provide you with a little insight into what open source software is and
    what it means to you.</para>
    <para>In a nutshell, open source software provides users with access to
    software source code. By source code, we mean the programming files that
    form the basis for a software product. Open source software is different
    from closed source software, in that closed source software locks up its
    source code and hides it from end users. Traditionally, closed source
    software has been the more common form of commercial "boxed" software
    products that you would pick up at your local office store. A result of
    the open source movement has been several licensing and distribution
    models:</para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Community license</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Applications are free to anyone and developed as Projects in
          large groups based on public input.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Dual license</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>A combination of free and commercial applications. A company
          may provide some software tools that are free to the public, while
          others are sold commercially.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Shared source license</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Commercial software where the source code may be viewed;
          however, there is no ability to make changes to the code.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <note>
      <para>xTuple software generally falls under the second category: "dual
      license." That's because we offer both free and commercial applications,
      with our source code available for review and change.</para>
    </note>
    <para>Still wondering what all this means to you? Well, what it means is
    that the software we've created has grown based on direct feedback from
    YOU, our user community - whether you're a paying Customer or not.</para>
    <para>At xTuple, we don't hide our work from public scrutiny. Rather, we
    present our work for all to see. We do this to promote shared insight into
    how we can continue to improve the software to make your job easier. In
    fact, on the xTuple community website we encourage you to provide direct
    feedback regarding bugs you've found or features you may find useful in
    the future. We also invite you to share your success stories and tips and
    tricks. In this way, you can reach out and help other xTuple community
    members.</para>
    <para>And, If you are an IT professional and a bit of a code jockey, you
    can even make changes to the source code on your local copy. Many of our
    greatest enhancements have been sponsored by our Customers&mdash;and these
    changes have been rolled into the final product so that other users can
    benefit from the improvements. This means our tools and products are not
    designed solely by xTuple engineers. They are also designed by the people
    who use them everyday. We at xTuple encourage you to learn more about the
    community and get involved on the <ulink
    url="www.xtuple.org">xTuple.org</ulink> website. Rather than quietly
    grumbling to yourself about things you think could be better, reach out to
    fellow community members to find out how to make these changes
    happen!</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>xTuple Application Architecture</title>
    <para>The xTuple applications are designed on a two-tier system:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Graphical client built using the open source Qt development
        framework</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Database server running on the open source PostgreSQL
        database</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>All of the xTuple business logic resides in the database, so there
    is no middle tier (i.e., Java/application server). And the client is
    "thin": since Qt and the PostgreSQL database are cross-platform solutions,
    the application can be installed on Mac, Windows, or Linux
    machines&mdash;in any combination you prefer.</para>
    <para>Installation of xTuple is easy and painless. Once you download the
    software, you then run the xTuple graphical client out of the directory it
    resides in. The same xTuple client can connect to a database for any of
    the xTuple ERP editions: PostBooks, Standard, or Manufacturing. Upgrading
    from one edition to the next involves little more than running a
    two-minute script on your database. The simplicity of the upgrade process
    illustrates the point that xTuple maintains a single code base for all of
    its ERP editions. Doing so enables our community of open source users to
    share and work together in one online hub for all the xTuple
    products.</para>
    <para>There are several layers of security available with xTuple ERP. You
    can utilize a Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) connection, and you can also
    enable an enhanced authentication mechanism which scrambles your users'
    passwords. In addition, you can also assign individual privileges with the
    system in as much detail as you see fit for your operation.</para>
  </section>
</preface>
