<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2010 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>Projects</title>
  <para>In order to begin utilizing the Time and Expense features, you must
  create Projects to track time and expenses against. xTuple provides the
  ability to create basic Projects with links to Tasks and Project progress
  and budget review. In this chapter the following topics will be covered, as
  they relate to Time and Expense.</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Creating Projects</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Creating Project Tasks</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Project Reporting</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Once a Project is created, you can begin entering Time and Expense
  Sheets!</para>
  <section>
    <title>Create Project</title>
    <para>The first thing that needs to get done before you can start entering
    time and expenses is to create a Project to associate these costs with.
    Keep in mind, you cannot create Time Sheets without a Project. To create a
    Project follow these steps:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Go to this path: <guimenuitem>CRM &gt; Project &gt;
        New...</guimenuitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/project.png" />
          </imageobject>
          <caption>Project</caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Complete the Project information and refer to the <ulink
        url="http://www.xtuple.org/docs/reference-guide">xTuple ERP Reference
        Guide</ulink> for further details regarding specific Project
        fields.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If you want the Project to appear on the Time Sheet, the
          Project status must be "In-Process."</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Create Project Tasks</title>
    <para>In order to track time and expenses against a Project, a Task will
    be required for Time Sheet entries. When selecting the Project "Tasks"
    tab, you will be presented with the following screen:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/projecttasklist.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Project Task List</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>From the Task list, simply select the NEW button to create a new
    Task. You can then enter the Task description and other details on the
    following screen:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/projecttask.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Project Task</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Under the "Billing" tab you can specify a Customer, billing rate,
    and an Item that will appear as default values on Time Sheets.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/taskbilling.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Project Billing</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>When you are done entering billing information, select the SAVE to
    close and exit the screen.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Project Reporting</title>
    <para>As Project team members are entering time and expenses against a
    Project, there are a few different areas where the Project Manager can
    monitor and track this information on the Project itself. First open an
    existing Project by following these steps:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Go to this path: <guimenuitem>CRM &gt; Project &gt;
        List...</guimenuitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Project and click the ACTIVITY button on the "Schedule"
        tab</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following screen will appear:</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/projectactivity.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Project Activity</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>The Project Activity report illustrates current Project activities
    associated with Sales Orders, Purchase Orders, Work Orders, and Invoices
    resulting from services billed out via Time and Expense.</para>
    <para>Next select the "Summary" tab on the Project. This tab shows a
    summary of the time and expenses which have been recorded against the
    Project thus far. Time and Expenses can be entered via a Time Sheet or a
    Project Manager can manually enter this data on specific Tasks.</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/projectsummary.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Project Summary</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Finally, if you need a break down of time and expenses by Task,
    select the "Tasks" tab. You will again be presented with the following
    screen:</para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/projecttasklist.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Project Task List</caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>Click the PRINT button and you will be able to view a itemized list
    of Tasks that lists the status of each Task and the actual hours versus
    budgeted hours.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
